

# MD. TANZID HOSSAIN



+880 1533-142671



tanzidhossainofiicial@gmail.com







### **SKILLS**

### **GENERAL:**

- PROBLEM SOLVING
- CRITICAL THINKING
- QUICK LEARNER
- TIME MANAGEMENT
- ADAPTABILITY
- TEAM PLAYER
- MICROSOFT OFFICE
- STRONG COMMUNICATION

#### **TECHNICAL:**

- FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT USING BOOTSTRAP, PHP & MYSQL
- MERN STACK
- WORDPRESS THEME DEVELOPMENT
- SOFTWARE TESTING AND QUALITY ASSURANCE (SELENIUM)
- DATA STRUCTURES & ALGORITHMS
- NETWORK VULNERABILITIES AND THREAT DETECTION
- PRIVACY AND DATA CONFIDENTIALITY
- INTERNET OF THINGS
- VERSION CONTROLLING (GIT)
- SDLC PROCESS
- AGILE METHODOLOGY
- WATERFALL METHODOLOGY

## CHECK OUT MY GITHUB PROFILE FOR PROJECTS:

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/MDTANZIDHOS SAIN

### **OBJECTIVE**

My Goal is to become a successful expert in the field of 'Software Engineering' & 'Information Technology' by channelizing my technical knowledge and skills to ensure personal and professional growth and to contribute to the prosperity of the organization.

### **EDUCATION**

2018-PRESENT

UNITED INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY (UIU)
Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

Major: Software Engennering

Completed credit: 134/137 (last trimester)

• 2016-2018

BIRSRESHTHO MUNSHI ABDUR ROUF PUBLIC COLLEGE

Group: Science | Result: 4.33

2015-2016

MOTIJHEEL MODEL HIGH SCHOOL AND COLLEGE

Group: Science | Result: 5.00

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

2023-PRESENT
 CARRIASTIC
 Web-Developer (Intern)

• 2022-2023

MINDPLANNER LTD

Wordpress theme-Developer

### **TRAINING**

Full Stack Web Development (2021)

**Duration:** 8 Months

Coordinator: Omar Faruk, Sikhbe Shobai.

**Cybersecurity Essentials (2020)** 

**Duration:** 4 weeks

Coordinator: Dr. Mohammad Mamun Elahi, UIU Cisco Networking Academy.

Introduction to Cybersecurity (2020)

**Duration:** 3 weeks

Coordinator: Dr. Mohammad Mamun Elahi, UIU Cisco Networking Academy.

Introduction to IoT (2020)

**Duration: 3** weeks

Coordinator: Dr. Mohammad Mamun Elahi, UIU Cisco Networking Academy.

**Search Engine Optimization (2018)** 

**Duration:** 3 weeks

Coordinator: Md Faruk Khan, Online Batch.

PERSONAL DETAILS

FATHER'S NAME: MD. AMZAD HOSSAIN MOTHER'S NAME: MAKSUDA AKHTER

**BLOOD GROUP**: A+

NATIONALITY : BANGLADESHI

DOB : 21/2/2001 RELIGION : ISLAM

ADRESS: 124/127 JANATA HOUSING, MIRPUR, DHAKA 1217

REFERENCE

NAME: DR. SUMAN AHMMED

**DESIGNATION:** ASST. PROFESSOR, CSE

DIRECTOR, CENTER FOR DEVELOPMENT OF IT PROFESSIONALS (CDIP)

**ORGANIZATION: UNITED INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY** 

**CONTACT:** +8801765049901

E-MAIL: SUMAN@CSE.UIU.AC.BD